(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-06T06:00:36.327464",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
王国内で繰り広げられる音楽祭。
A music festival held within the kingdom.
この日を待ってたと言ばかりに国民達は各々で応援する為の道具を用意し、
As if waiting eagerly for this very day, the citizens prepared items to show their support,
そして、広場へと向かいました。
and headed toward the town square.
ほっと一息お茶漬けですわよ
Taking a breather, it's ochazuke!
いつもの場所から
From our usual spot,
元気にせーのでごあいさつ
let's cheerfully say hello together!
お届けしよ
Let's deliver it—
始めましょうわ
let's get started!
おしゃべりはしてゲームとすごす
Chatting and gaming away,
そんな毎日が愛おしくて
those everyday moments are so dear.
あれもこれも手を出したくなり勝ちです
I tend to want to try all sorts of things!
歌とかステージはまだまだ恥ずかしいけど
Singing on stage is still a bit embarrassing, but...
ささやかなってほらお届けますよ
See? I'm delivering this humble tune to you,
この声を
with this voice!
Say! (Yeah!)
ほらその顔上げてみんなで手をとれば
Lift your face and let's all take hands,
Dive! (Foo!)
まだまだ未知の地平線
To a yet-unseen horizon,
世界を越えよう
let's cross over the world!
(せーの)
(Ready, set)
Say! (Yeah!)
ほらおもしろ事も止まらない全力ですから
Because we're going all out with endless fun,
夢をかき換えたら追いかけ続けよう
Let's rewrite our dreams and keep chasing them!
ともにつなぐファンファーレ
A fanfare connecting us together,
ちょっとやらかしたときでも
Even when I mess up a little,
気持ち切り替えてほっとしちゃう広がりには
Changing my mood, letting out a sigh of relief,
背伸びをして
stretching up tall,
お腹減ったらすぐもぐもぐと
and when I get hungry, munching right away—
お茶の間いますこんなおやつで
That's the kind of snack-time guest I am!
黒いあの子には内緒にしてほしいです
I want to keep this a secret from that dark friend.
なかまのちからとおともだちのみなさんと
With the power of friends and all my companions,
かなえたい想いは言葉にしてひとつひとつ
turning every dream into words, one by one.
Say! (Yeah!)
ほらその手上げてみんなで輪になれば
Lift your hands and let's form a circle,
Dive! (Foo!)
これからの夢の先へ向かおう
Heading beyond our dreams from here on out!
(もういっかい)
(Once more!)
Say! (Yeah!)
ほらおもしろ事も止まらない全力ですから
Because we're going all out with endless fun,
大好きな想いがあふれるほど
Overflowing with so much love,
ともにつなぐファンファーレ
A fanfare connecting us together.
ほっとひと息 お茶ですよ
Take a deep breath, it's time for tea!
いつもの場所から 元気にせーのでご挨拶
Greeting you cheerfully from our usual place!
おっはこーんでーすよー！(^・ω・^§)ノ
Good morning everyone!
始めましょうか！
Shall we begin?
おしゃべりをしてゲームで過ごす
Chatting and spending time playing games,
そんな毎日が愛しくて
I cherish every single day like that.
あれもこれも手を出したくなりがちです
Always wanting to get my hands on everything.
歌とかステージは まだまだ恥ずかしいけど
Singing and stages are still a bit embarrassing, but
支え合ってほら 届きますよこの声を
Supporting each other, look, this voice will reach you!
say!
ほら その顔上げて みんなで手を取れば
Hey, lift your face and if we all hold hands,
dive!
まだまだ道の途中 世界を越えよう
Still on the way there, let's cross the world!
say!
ほら 推しお仕事も止まらない全力ですから！
Hey, even my oshi work never stops, I'm giving it my all!
夢を書きかえたら 追いかけ続けようともに
If we rewrite our dreams, let's keep chasing them together.
繋ぐ
Connecting,
ファンファレ
Fanfare!
ちょーっと柔らかい時でも
Even when things are a bit soft and gentle,
気持ち切り替えて
Changing my mindset,
ぼーっとしてしまう昼下がりは
An afternoon daydreaming off into space,
ひるこーんでーすよー！ (^・ω・^§)ノ
Good afternoon everyone!
背伸びをして お腹へったらすぐモグモグとお茶の合間
Stretching my back, when I get hungry I snack right between tea time.
こんなおやつで 黒いあの子には内緒にして欲しいです
I'd like to keep this snack a secret from that dark one.
仲間の力とお友達のみなさんと
With the power of friends and everyone here,
叶えたい想いは言葉にして一つ一つ
Every single wish I want to grant, expressed in words.
say!
ほら その手を上げて みんなで輪になれば
Hey, raise your hands and if we form a circle,
dive!
まだまだ成長途中 問題ないでしょ？
Still growing up, no problem right?
say!
ほら 明るく元気な心が取り柄ですから！
Hey, because my cheerful and bright heart is my best trait!
へぼみな時も輝き続けようともに
Even in down moments, let's keep shining together.
繋ぐ
Connecting,
アンコール
Encore!
何もかもが新しくて右も左もわからない時も
Even when everything is brand new and I'm lost,
頑張れたのは一人じゃないから
I was able to try my best because I'm not alone.
一つ一つ応援が後押しになって
Each and every cheering message pushed me forward,
一歩ずつでも私は自分らしく磨いていくfuture
Step by step, I'll polish my own unique future.
答えもイメージもまだまだ手探りしても
Even while searching blindly for answers and images,
響き合ってほら 世界は今色めいて
Resonating together, look, the world is colorful now.
say!
さあ その顔上げて みんなで手を取れば
Now, lift your face and if we all hold hands,
dive!
これから夢の先へ駆け出そう
Let's dash forward beyond our dreams.
say!
ほら 推しお仕事も止まらない全力ですから！
Hey, even my oshi work never stops, I'm giving it my all!
大好きな想いがあふれそうなほどともに
With feelings of love overflowing together,
繋ぐ
Connecting,
ファンファレール！
Fanfare!
甘くほろ苦い夢
A sweet and bittersweet dream,
“これでいい”か “これがいい”か
'Is this fine?' or 'This is what I want?'
折れかけたあの日
On that day when I was about to break,
ここに間違いはなくて
There was no mistake here,
正解もなくて自分次第って
No single correct answer, it's all up to me.
怖くて仕方ないけど
It's so scary I can't help it, but
“誰か”じゃない“君”と見たい
I want to see it with 'you', not just 'someone'.
景色は鮮明で…
The scenery is vivid...
それじゃあ、ここで足踏みなんかしていられらんないじゃんっ！
So there's no way I can just mark time right here!
oh yeah！！
Oh yeah!!
無数の星の中
Among countless stars,
oh yeah！！
Oh yeah!!
光は君がくれた
You gave me that light.
oh yeah！！ もっと！
Oh yeah!! More!
yeah 超えていけるさっ！
Yeah, we can surpass it!
oh yeah！！ supernova 起こせ、今！
Oh yeah!! Ignite a supernova right now!
oh yeah！！ 何度だって翔べる
Oh yeah!! We can soar no matter how many times.
oh yeah！！ これは紛れもなく僕らの軌跡
Oh yeah!! This is without a doubt our trajectory.
hi friends！！
Hi friends!!
心、泣きじゃくる日でも
Even on days when my heart is crying,
いつだってここにおいで？
You can always come here, right?
強がりはらしくないよっ！
Putting up a tough front isn't like you!
“ひとり”じゃない“君”もほら
You're not 'alone', look, you too
僕等、手取り合って
We'll hold hands together
笑おうっ！叫ぼうっ！
Let's laugh! Let's shout!
あの宇宙の向こうへ
To the other side of that universe!
oh yeah！！
Oh yeah!!
無数の星の中
Among countless stars,
oh yeah！！
Oh yeah!!
交わした約束も
The promise we exchanged,
oh yeah！！ きっと
Oh yeah!! Surely
yeah 叶えられるさっ！
Yeah, we can make it come true!
oh yeah！！ supernova 駆けろ、今！
Oh yeah!! Run through the supernova, now!
oh yeah！！ 誰一人欠かせない
Oh yeah!! Not a single person missing,
oh yeah！！ あの日描いた夢の先まで
Oh yeah!! All the way beyond the dream we sketched that day.
hi friends！！
Hi friends!!
こんな現在を愛せるように
So that I can love the present like this,
君に向けて謳おう 心が叫んでるっ！
I'll sing out to you, my heart is crying out!
oh yeah！！
Oh yeah!!
無数の星の中
Among countless stars,
oh yeah！！
Oh yeah!!
光は君がくれた
You gave me that light.
oh yeah！！ もっと！
Oh yeah!! More!
yeah 超えていけるさっ！
Yeah, we can surpass it!
oh yeah！！ supernova 起こせ、今！
Oh yeah!! Ignite a supernova right now!
oh yeah！！ 何度だって翔べる
Oh yeah!! We can soar no matter how many times.
oh yeah！！ これは紛れもなく僕らの軌跡
Oh yeah!! This is without a doubt our trajectory.
“普通”も“あたりまえ”も無い
There's no such thing as 'ordinary' or 'taken for granted',
君が君らしく在れるように
So that you can exist truly as yourself,
もっとっ！ずっとっ！届けようっ！
More! Always! Let's make it reach!
不思議と怖いは無いんだ
Surprisingly, there's no fear left,
綺麗事、絵空事でもない
It's neither sweet talk nor empty idealism,
さあ、行こうっ！
Now, let's go!
この物語は終わらないっ！
This story will never end!
oh yeah！！
Oh yeah!!
無数の星の中
Among countless stars,
oh yeah！！
Oh yeah!!
光は君がくれた
You gave me that light.
oh yeah！！ もっと！
Oh yeah!! More!
yeah 超えていけるさっ！
Yeah, we can surpass it!
oh yeah！！ supernova 起こせ、今！
Oh yeah!! Ignite a supernova right now!
oh yeah！！ 何度だって翔べる
Oh yeah!! We can soar no matter how many times.
oh yeah！！ これは紛れもなく僕らの軌跡
Oh yeah!! This is without a doubt our trajectory.
今この愛せるように 君に向けて歌おう 心が告げて
So that I can love this moment now, I'll sing towards you, my heart tells me so.
oh yeah！！ 無数の星の中
Oh yeah!! Among countless stars,
oh yeah！！ 光は君がくれた
Oh yeah!! You gave me that light.
oh yeah！！ もっと！
Oh yeah!! More!
yeah 超えていけるさっ！
Yeah, we can surpass it!
oh yeah！！ supernova 起こせ、今！
Oh yeah!! Ignite a supernova right now!
oh yeah！！ 何度だって翔べる
Oh yeah!! We can soar no matter how many times.
oh yeah！！ これは紛れもなく僕らの軌跡
Oh yeah!! This is without a doubt our trajectory.
oh yeah！！ supernova 駆けろ、今！
Oh yeah!! Run through the supernova, now!
oh yeah！！ 誰一人欠かせない
Oh yeah!! Not a single person missing,
oh yeah！！ あの日描いた夢の先まで
Oh yeah!! All the way beyond the dream we sketched that day.
hi friends！！
Hi friends!!
生まれ落ちた意味 後悔してんの？
What's the meaning of being born? Do you regret it?
画面越しにね 僕の姿ね
Through the screen, my figure is...
キミになれない surrender！
You can't become me, surrender!
light me up 教えてくれ あの時の雨の日よは
Light me up, teach me about that rainy day...
hold me down 追いかけて
Hold me down, chase after me.
狂わせ 目を細めた おいで
Stirred up, narrowing my eyes, come here.
キミはヒラヒラヒラ ちりついた瞬間は 花びらヒラヒラヒラ 漂う in my head
Scattered moments are flower petals, drifting in my head.
ここは劣等 祭 裸 晒して ah ローロー とキミと踊りたいのさ 「滅相ない」を言わないで ah ローロー と示して 本能
Here is an inferior festival, exposing bare skin...
たまや たまや 明日に見せつけて たまや たまや 導火線になって たまや たまや もう朝ね
Tamaya, show it off to tomorrow, become the fuse.
はーい！ということで、しょっぱなから2曲歌わせていただきました！
Hi there! So, we sang two songs right off the bat!
みなさん、こんばんはー！きーつねー！
Good evening, everyone! Ki-tsu-ne-!
フブキングダムの国王、白神フブキです！いぇーい！
I'm Shirakami Fubuki, the king of Fubukingdom! Yay!
見てるー！はーい！
Watching? Hai!
ちょっとね、もう暑いや
Man, it's getting hot.
えー、本日はですね、フブキングダムの秘密解禁ということで、みなさんね、ソワソワしてるんじゃないかと思います。
I think you're all feeling restless for this secret opening.
ハッシュタグはこちら。「秘密解禁フブキングダム」です。
Here's the hashtag: "#HimitsuKaikinFubukingdom".
なんかすごいソシャゲのタイトルみたいでかっこいいなと思ってつけました。いぇーい！よろしくお願いします！
It sounded cool like a gacha game title. Yay! Please look forward to it!
さて、ちょっとね、まず1つ目の重大発表じゃないけどプチお披露目がございます。
Now, first, not quite a major announcement, but a mini unveiling.
さて、どこにいるかな？あ、いたいたいたいた！おいでー！わー！
Now, where are they? Oh, there they are! Come here! Wow!
なんとなんと、おまえらみんな、国民がこんなにかわいいお身体を手に入れたぞー！
And lo and behold, you all have gotten such cute bodies!
みんなかわいいやんけ！かわいい！よかったねみんな。みんなもついにこうやって白神の横に立つ時がきたんだ！
You guys are so cute! The time has come to stand beside Shirakami!
わー！かわいい！うれしいね！うれしいの？あーよかったー！
Wa-! So cute! I'm so happy! I'm so glad!
で、実はね、このスカーフはね、JPズコメなんだけどね、実の裏にですね、海外の、海外ズコメフレンドも実はいるというね。
This scarf is the JP su-com, but overseas friends are also here.
我が代表としてJPズコメの、いつものスカーフのスコムにお越しいただきました。
As our representative, they came to the JP su-com's usual scarf.
で、さらにさらに、後ろをご覧ください！ふぶら……ごう、言うておる！顔でかすぎんだろ！
And what's more, look behind! Fubura... gou? Your face is huge!
ほらね、フブラもですね、いつスかーいんにかけてくれました。やっほー！顔見えんな、建物の間から見える！
See, Fubura hung it too. Yahhoo! Can see through the buildings!
かわいいやんけ！ねえ！ということで、今日は一緒にね、重大発表していきましょう！
So cute! Right! So today let's make the major announcements together!
告知いっぱいありますので、じゃあちょっと1番ちょっとすごい告知からいっちゃおうかなって
There are tons of announcements, so let's start with the big one!
フォーティシモの雨降る 役不足ワイパー 軒立だけアクセルのせ 駆け抜ける摩天楼 ドライブ
Fortissimo rain falling, insufficient wiper, driving through skyscrapers.
あ、の、お前ら……
Hey, you guys...
ピピピピピピピ……
Pipipipipipi...
え、何何何？ピピ？あ、じゃあないよ！
Eh, what what what? Pipi? Ah, no it's not!
全くフブさんたら！
Good grief, Fubuki-san!
え、何？フブさん、うるさいよ！
Eh, what? Fubuki-san, you're loud!
そっちじゃない！
That's not it!
全く！困ったさんなんだから！
Good grief! You're such a troublesome person!
何がだよ！何をシレッと重大告知しようとしてんだよ！
What do you mean! Why are you casually making a major announcement?!
だって重大告知する配信だから！
Because it's a stream for major announcements!
いやいやそんな引っ張るに決まってるじゃな最後まで！
Of course you drag it out until the very end!
当たり前だよ！引っ張らせますよ！
Naturally! We'll make you drag it out!
のびのびだよ、のびのび。
Drag it out, drag it out.
ええ、そうてかどうしたら二人とも、ハロウィンはもう終わったんだよ！
Eh, besides, why you two—Halloween is already over!
終わってない！
It's not over!
ハリキリトニー一个、そんなこともないよ！
There's no such thing!
メチャクチャメチャクチャハロウィンピピピピプエダよ！
It's totally a messy Halloween!
何しに来たんだ、ほんとに！話してきただけ？
What did you really come here for? Just to talk?
重大告知をさせないために邪魔をしに来ました！これから魔法をかけるので覚悟してください！
We came to stop your major announcement! Be prepared for our magic!
魔法？魔法使えるの？そうです！え、そうなの？
Magic? You can use magic? That's right!
当たり前でしょ！当たり前ってなんだよ！決まってるじゃん！私たちだけこの杖持ってるからね。
Of course! Because only we hold these wands.
確かに何その杖？
True, what are those wands?
マジックショップで買ったんだよ！
We bought them at a magic shop!
何してんの？でも、そんな強くないよね、その杖。
What are you doing? But those wands aren't very strong.
まあ魔法をかけて邪魔をしてしまうという役割なんですね、我々は。
Our role is to cast magic and get in the way.
やめてよ！人の告知で好き勝手して！
Stop it! Doing whatever you want during someone else's announcement!
だって邪魔しちゃううるさいよ！邪魔しちゃうのかわいい！
Because we'll get in the way! You're loud! Getting in the way is cute!
なんかスコム？スコムだよ！いじめないで！
What, su-com? It's su-com! Don't bully them!
ほら小さいかわいいものをいじめないで！
Look, don't bully small, cute things!
かわいい
Cute.
いや、立ち向かうのはまずい。
No, confronting them is bad.
見込みない、見込みない！
No chance, no chance!
かわいいね
So cute!
まだまだ、まだ!
Still more, still more!
ということでね、まあ皆さんもちょっとね
So, everyone, um...
こちらに、ほうぼうさんはこっち、こっち、え、何？
Over here, Hoobou-san is this way... wait, what?
なに？こっちにこっち
What? This way, this way.
え、何？ほうぼうにね、ちゃんと、何が始まるんです？
Huh? What? Hoobou-san, properly... what is starting?
フブキングだよ！
It's Fubuking!
これ間違えるとちょっと色々ね、やばいことになっちゃう
If we get this wrong, a lot of bad things will happen...
うちらもうちょっと後ろだよ
We're a bit further back!
あ、何？何が始まるんです？
Ah, what? What's starting?
それじゃあ、やってみましょう
Well then, let's try it.
はい
Okay!
せーの、ビビでバビでブーわ！
Ready, set, Bibidi-Babidi-Boo!
何？何？なんか来た！
What? What? Something's coming!
うおー！やったー！すっげー！
Whoa! Yay! Amazing!
ふう、力を使ったぜ
Phew, I used my power.
やったー
Yay!
いやー、かなりの魔を消費したね
Man, that consumed quite a bit of magic.
え？白くん？あれ？あれ？
Huh? Shiro-kun? Huh? What?
あれ！？大スクープになってる！
Huh?! It's a huge scoop!
え！？フブさん！フブさん！
Eh?! Fubu-san! Fubu-san!
あ、こっちは、フブさん、踊れーい！
Ah, over here, Fubu-san, dance!
何、踊る？
What, dancing?
結構セクシーな感じ、やめろ！お前ら、踊りすぎ！
Pretty sexy... Stop it! You guys, dancing too much!
踊り踊んないから
We're not dancing!
セクシーだ！これ、なんだこれ、ちんちくりんは
So sexy! What is this, this shorty?
なんだこれ、ちっちゃい、ちんちくりんなんだ
What is this, it's tiny, a shorty.
フブさんはこんなにちっちゃかったんだね
Fubu-san, you were this small?
ちっちゃくねえよ
I'm not small!
あ、ちっちゃかったね。おチビちゃんにする
Ah, you were small. I'll make you a tiny one.
なんだ、なんだこれまじで
What, what is this seriously?
はい、ということでね、まあ、元に
Right, so, well, to get back...
戻りたかったら、ミコたちとゲームをして、この魔法を解きなさい！
If you want to return to normal, play games with us and break this magic!
それでは、いきますよ。題して
Well then, here we go. Entitled...
フブ抜き対決
Fubunuki Battle
なんか、ケツきた
Wait, Ketsu came?
ということで説明をお願いします
So please explain the rules.
ルールの説明まいります
I will explain the rules.
目の前に、星のペア、ハートのペア、ジョーカー、フブキングの絵柄合わせて6枚のカードがありますよね、皆さん。
In front of you, there are 6 cards total: star pair, heart pair, joker, and Fubuking, right everyone?
お互いのカードを引き合ってペアの図柄をゲットしたら捨てて、最後の1枚「フブキングカード」→勝利！「ジョーカー」→負け。これらのカードを3枚ずつ対戦する2人に配ります。
Draw cards from each other, discard pairs. Last card: 'Fubuking' -> Win! 'Joker' -> Loss. 3 cards are dealt to each player.
2人にはこれらのカードを引き合うゲームをしてもらい、ペアの図柄を揃えたら捨てていき、最後の1枚としてフブキングカードを持っていることができれば勝利、ジョーカーを持っていたら負けとなります。
They will play a card-drawing game, discarding matched pairs, and holding the Fubuking card last means victory, while the Joker means defeat.
通常のババ抜きと違って、手札の図柄が揃った場合は続けざまにカードを引くことができます。なるほど、そして手札がなくなったとしても最後まで引いて勝負を決めることです。
Unlike Old Maid, if cards match, you can draw again. And even if your hand runs out, you draw to the very end to decide the match.
なるほどね。何言ってるかかんないと思うけど、遊んでみないとわかんないわけ。遊んでみないといけませんわね。
I see. You probably don't get it, but you won't know until you play. We have to play.
そうよ。だから注意しないとすぐに負けちゃう。そんなフブのために私用意しました。
That's right. So if you aren't careful, you'll lose right away. For such Fubu, I prepared something.
じゃ、シャッフルチャンス！シャッフルチャンスとは、自分がピンチ、相手の手札を入れ替えることができる機能です。もし使いたい時にはゲーム中に「シャッフルチャンス！」と叫んでくれれば、私が
Then, Shuffle Chance! A feature where if you're in a pinch, you can swap hands. If you want to use it, shout 'Shuffle Chance!' and I will...
ふぶぶぶぶぶってやるのでね。なるほどね。シャッフルチャンス！これ一番おっちこんぶだな？
do 'Fubububububu'. I see. Shuffle Chance! Is this the most important combo?
ふぶさんもね、ちゃんと覚えてね。おっちこんぶだな。ただし、残りの手札が1枚の時にシャッフルチャンスは使えないものとします。
Fubu-san, remember it too. It's 'ottikonbu'. However, Shuffle Chance cannot be used when you have 1 card left.
2枚ないとダメなんだ。そうですね。じゃないとちょっとね、あの、ぬるげーになっちゃうんで。あ、なるほどね。このシャッフルチャンスはゲーム始める前にジャンケンをして勝った方に与えられます。逆に負けた方は先にカードを引く権利を与えられますというルールになっております。
You need 2 cards, otherwise it becomes too easy. Ah, I see. Shuffle Chance is given to the winner of rock-paper-scissors before the game starts, while the loser draws first.
じゃあ、ちょっとやっていきますか？
So, shall we try it out?
そうですね。あ、ね、これちょっとシャッフルチャンス忘れないようにしなきゃいけないね。絶対忘れないでくださいね。じゃんけんでね。さてさてさてさて、ということで、あのスコムブのふぶ、ふふぶのスコムブ
That's right. Ah, we mustn't forget Shuffle Chance. Decided by rock-paper-scissors. Now then, the Skomb's Fubu, Fubu's Skomb...
どっちでもいいんですけど、つまり、このメンバーで勝負！ということで、じゃあちょっとね、ふぶさんっていうかスコムブ、ここに入りなさい。
Either is fine, meaning we battle with these members! So Fubu-san, or rather Skomb, get in here.
え？入りなさい。ふぶさんはどっち？ふぶさん、こっち。え、え、みこさんとチーム組むってこと？
Eh? Get in. Which one is Fubu-san? Fubu-san, here. Eh, Miko-san, you're teaming up?
いや、それではないよ。違う違うよ。
No, it's not like that. No, no.
早いことね。じゃあ、まず1回目はエースコンブ、かっこふぶさんね。ふぶさん
Fast, right? Well, first time is Ace Kombu (Fubu-san). Fubu-san...
こんにちは、スコムブさん。白髪美だよ。
Hello, Skomb-san. Shirakami-bi.
白髪美だよ。あ、ふぶきさん
Shirakami-bi. Ah, Fubuki-san.
まぎらわしい。最悪。
Confusing. Worst.
じゃあね、まずまあ真剣勝負ということで、ジャンケンからやっていきますかね。
Well then, first, since it's a serious match, let's start with rock-paper-scissors.
か？
Okay?
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay, okay.
よ、オッケー。
Yo, okay?
最初はぐう、じゃんけんぽい！
First is rock-paper-scissors!
チョキ！
Cho-ki!
パーだろ、それ。
That's scissors, right?
チョキだよ。
It's choki!
お前、チョキ…
Wait, choki?
チョキ、チョキ知ってる？ チョキしてるか？
Do you know choki?
You know choki?
っていうことにするかっていうことにするか。
Let's make it so you are doing choki.
はい。
Yeah.
うん、ま、チョキね。
Right, it's choki, then.
はい、そうですよ。
Yeah, that's right.
パー！
Pa!
本当にパー？
Is it really pa?
パー。
Pa.
グーです。
It's gu.
グーに。
Gu.
勝った。
勝ちました。
I won.
負けました。 ということで、勝ち。
So I won!
ということで、勝ち。
じゃあ、えー、ホブさんの勝ちということで。
So, I won!
じゃあ、白上かシャッフルチャンスできるんだ。
That means Shirakami gets the shuffle chance!
そうだな。 シャッフルチャンスをゲットした。
That's right, she gets the shuffle chance!
じゃあ、すいちゃん先こうね。
So Sui-chan goes first?
はい、よっし、頑張るぞ。 いけるぞ。
Alright, let's do our best!
よし、じゃあ準備いいですか？
Alright, are you ready?
はーい！
Yes!
Yes.
はい、じゃああの、皆さんね、ついて、ついて、ついて、ついて。
Alright, then everyone follow along!
カードの位置を確認して。
Check out the card positions.
じゃあ、まず…
So first...
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
みこさん。
Mikochi.
はいはいはい。 引き込みどうですか？
How is the placement?
いやあ、まあ、ちょっとね、最近運がいいような悪いようなだけども、ここで運を取り戻そうと思いますよ。
Well, you know, my luck has been...
太く見えないよ、そんな格好で言われても。
You don't look lucky with that outfit.
うせえ！
Usee!
パンツ見るぞ！
Let's see your cards!
やめろよ！
Stop it!
じゃあ、すいちゃんの引き込みどうですか？
So, how about Sui-chan's placement?
全く。 運といえば私。
I have zero luck.
私といえば運。
When it comes to me, it's luck.
カード対決でしょ、すいちゃん。
Right? You're playing with cards, right, Sui-chan?
分かってますよね。だから私は
You know it, right? So I am...
今日ここで勝って
going to win here today...
フブキ
and make Shirakami...
お前に重大告知をさせる！
pay a heavy penalty!
最低だよ。
The worst!
最低だ、マジで最低だ。
The absolute worst!
マジで最低だ。
Seriously, the worst!
ひどいすね。
That's terrible.
ということで
So, with that said...
せんかのすいちゃん、まず1枚選んでください。
Sui-chan's first pick, please choose one!
勝負開始！
Let the games begin!
さてみこちゃんはどれを選ぶ？
Mikochi, which one will you choose?
フブキさん、どれ引いたらいいと思う？
Fubuki-san, which one do you think is good?
一番右。
The far right.
おすすめ？
Recommendation?
ほんと？
Really?
おすすめだよ。
My recommendation.
始まりましたよ、シンジさん始まりました。
Here we go, Shinji-san, it's starting!
右かな？
Is the far right okay?
周りはやめたほうがいいよ。
Maybe you shouldn't choose the right.
右、左はやめたほうがいい。
Right, left should be avoided.
やめたほうがいいよ。
You should avoid it.
こういうときは
So when it's like this,
食べれって言われたもんだろ。
you're told to eat, right?
これか？
Is that it?
それ？
This?
大丈夫かな？
Is it okay?
フブキの力で…
With all your might!
どうだ？
How is it?
それではどうですか？
So how is it?
転がったものが
The one that rolled over is...
おっ！星が出た！
Oh! A star!
星が出ました。
It's a star!
まあまあ、まだこれがあるんですかね？
Well, there's still more to come, right?
最後に残ってるが残ってないかだから悪いカードがね。
Finally, let's see if there are any left over,
え、まだ引けるんだよね、これは。
You can still draw, right?
うわあっ！
Oh, no!
シャッフル！
Shuffle!
シャッフル、シャッフル！
またシャッフル、またシャッフルするんですか。
You're shuffling again, Fubuki-san?
多すぎるだろ！
That's too much!
混ぜて混ぜて！
Mix it up, mix it up!
待って待って、私のカード！
Wait, wait, my cards!
混ぜて混ぜて！
Mix it up, mix it up!
よっし。
Alright.
なるほどね。
I see.
ふう、どうなったかな？
Phew, I wonder how it turned out.
おい、これ。 いいか、ちょっと見てみよう。
Hey, let's take a look.
おい、これまずいやんけ。
Hey, this is bad news.
え、待って。ってことは私、これはそろえてしまったらいけないんだよね。
Wait, does that mean if I match them all,
これはどうなの？シャッフルチャンスしたら白上はターンを消費したということなんですかね？
If I do a shuffle chance, does that mean Shirakami used up her turn?
まあまあ、ふぶちゃんのはい、どうすんのかな？
Well, Fubuki-chan is going to choose, right?
ふぶちゃんね、引いてください。そこは。はい。
Fubuki-chan, please pick one.
これは、私が今
As for me, right now...
ジョーカーを持たされたので、
I've been given the Joker.
この状態で私が絵柄を揃えてしまうと、
In this state, if I choose the right pattern,
私がジョーカーを持った状態になってしまうので、
I'll end up with the Joker,
フブキングダムも行かないといけないんですよ。
so I have to avoid Fubukingdom too.
そう、賢いじゃん。
Well, that's smart.
賢くないじゃないですか。
Isn't that smart?
こっち？ え、わかんないけど。
Which one? I don't know, but...
こっち？ こっちだったっけかな？
Which one? Was it this one?
ああ、こっちだわ。
Ah, it's this one.
真理を透視で見ためやろう。
Let's check the truth with clairvoyance.
な、め、め、めで。
Hey, eye, eye, with my eyes.
嘘ついてる。
Hey, you're lying!
見 て ない よ ね 。
You're not looking!
嘘ついてる時の目の動きをしっかりと見てください。
Pay attention to the eye movements when lying!
何も見せない。
I'm showing nothing.
何も見せないんだから！
I'm not showing anything!
こういうときは
When this happens,
こっちって言われたほうだよ。
you should pick this one.
これ！ 本当に？
This! Really?
ほんとに！
Really!
さあ、揃ったものはありますか？
So, do you have a match?
どうだ？
How is it?
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
やった！
Oh! You did it!
やったー！
Yay!
待って待って待って。
Hold on, hold on.
これ、ちょっと今からシャッフルするから。
I'm going to shuffle now, so...
シャッフル、シャッフル！
Shuffle!
シャッフル見ないよね、ふぶちゃん。
Everyone, don't look at the shuffle!
見ないよ。
I won't look.
可愛いね。
It's cute.
魔法使ってる。
You're using magic.
はい、じゃあ引いてください。
Alright, please draw one.
いいですよー。
Okay!
どれだ？
Which one is it?
えー、ちょっと、すいちゃんどれ教えて！
Hey, Sui-chan, tell me which one!
どれがおすすめ？
Which one is recommended?
え、待って。これ
Wait, this...
トムブス、トムブスっていう名の、フブキに入ってるトムブスを教えてくれよ。
Tombus, Tombus, come on, tell me which Tombus in Fubuki is the right one!
そうだよ、お前は仲間だ。
Hey, you're comrades!
だから分かるだろ？
So you should know.
どれがいいと思う？
Which one do you think is good?
わかる？ 教えて！
Tell me, please tell me!
わかるらしい。
I know!
トムブス、どうなってんだよ。
Tombus, what is going on here?
全部？
All of them?
全部全部おすすめ？
Are they all recommended?
いや、だめだ。
No, that won't work.
AIどうなってんだよ、これ。
AI, what is going on here?
待って、ふぶさん。
Wait, Fubuki-san,
私のすすめ、これ。
My recommendation is this one.
真ん中？
The middle?
真ん中だって。
The middle, then.
じゃあ真中おすすめされたから真中行くか。
Since the middle is recommended, should I go with the middle?
真中すいちゃんのおすすめを信じるよ。
I'll trust Sui-chan's recommendation.
さあ、どうだ！すいちゃんのおすすめを信じるぞ！
Alright, I believe in Sui-chan's recommendation!
揃って、いるんですか？
Did they match?
おーっ！
Oh!
揃ってる！
Correct!
揃ったということで、もう1回引くことができます！
Since they match, we get another draw!
じゃあ、ここからが勝負やで。
So, this is where it gets real.
どっちかなんだ！
Which one is it?
ええ！？
Eh?
どうしよう。
What should I do?
カードどれにするんですか？
Which one do you choose?
どうしようか。ええっ！？
What should I do? Eh?!
これはもういいのかい？どっちかで。
Is this okay? Which one?
どっち？すいちゃんのおすすめ？
Which one do you recommend, Suichan?
すいちゃんのおすすめ。
Suichan's recommendation.
どっち？
Which one?
こっちじゃん。こっち。
This one? This one.
どうも。
How about...
え、すいちゃんの顔見て！
Look at Suichan's face!
笑ってるよ。うりゃあ！
She's laughing!
すいちゃんの顔見てみ！
Look at Suichan's face!
こっちが正解かじゃん。
That means choosing this is correct?
うーん、どうかな。
Hmm, I wonder.
絶対正解。
It's definitely correct.
え？
Eh?
こっち。
This one.
どっち？じゃあこっちかな。
Which one? Then, this one maybe?
やと見せかけてこっち。
I'll pretend to choose this.
じゃあこっち！
Then, this one!
こっちだ！
This one!
きっと！
Surely!
白上のカードだ！
It's a Shirakami card!
どうだ！
Let's see!
ファイナルアンサーでいいじゃない。
Final answer, is this okay?
正解やった！
It's correct!
さあ、そのカードは！
Now, what is that card?
オープンッ！
Open!
フブキング！
Fubuki King!
やったあっ！
Awesome!
やったあ！勝った勝った！
I won! I won!
この私が勝つんだなんて。
I can't believe I'm going to win this.
お前バカだな！
You're an idiot!
バカかっ！バカ！バカ！
You idiot! Idiot!
うぇ、やめてください。
Hey, please stop!
やった！
Yay!
待って、この試合というか、このゲームは...
Wait, this match, or rather, this game...
白上の勝ち？
Is it Shirakami's win?
まあ、そういうことにはなれま...
Well, that's how it is.
勝者フブキ！
Winner Fubuki!
やったよこれで！スコムブ！
Yay! I did it with this!
これで我々元に戻してもらえるよ。
With this, can you return us to normal?
勝ったからね、しゃーないね。
We won, so no choice.
じゃあ、ゲームはここまで、ということで！
Well, the game ends here, so that's it!
勝った勝った！
We won! We won!
じゃあ、しょうがないからね。
Well, it can't be helped!
元に戻してあげますか。
We'll have you return us back.
ね。
Quietly...
ゆゆみこさんが戻すんだよ。
Yuyumiko-san is returning them.
戻す？え？どっち？え？
Return? Eh? Which?
早く戻して。
Hurry and return them.
フブキさんはカードは続けどジョーカーはできないよ。
Fubuki-san, you can keep the cards, but you can't do the Joker trick.
え、すいちゃんもカードことしかできないよ。
Eh, Suichan can only do cards too.
待って、二人とも揃ってポコチかよ！
Wait, both of us are out of cards too!
なっちゃったよ。こんなはずじゃなかったろ、どうなってんだよ。
Wait, how did it turn out like this?
だって、もうマナーが、マナーがないんだよ。
Because we have no manners anymore.
マナーがないんだよ。
What is this?
あ、待ってでもやるだけやってみよ。
Wait, even if there's no manners, let's just try doing it.
ね、ほらここ、魔法陣に、立って立って。立って立って。
Hey, look here, stand by the magic circle, stand, stand.
やるだけやる、やるやる。
Just do it, just do it.
よし。
Okay.
ビビデバビデブー！
Bibidebabidebu...
あ、だめだ。
Ah, it's no good.
だめだ。
It's no good!
だめじゃん！
ということでね、カードが足りないんだよね。
That means we're still short on cards!
どういうこと？
What does that mean?
みこちゃんたちはやお疲れモードかもしれないので、ここらへんで帰らせていただきます。
Miko-chan and the others might be tired, so let's wrap it up around here.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
まったね。このままでってことね。
Well, then we're leaving like this.
じゃあ帰るよ。
Well, we're leaving.
じゃあ、じゃあガチで帰るよ。
Let's really leave.
バイバーイ！待って待って待って待って！
Bye-bye! Wait, wait, wait, wait!
ごめんごめんごめん。こけた。
I fell down.
このちっちゃい体にな慣れてないよ、痛いよ。
My little body isn't used to this, it hurts!
マジで帰っちゃったんですけど、あの二人どうしよう。
I seriously turned back, but what about those two?
どうしようスコムブ。我々このままだよ。
What should I do, Scombu? We're stuck like this?
これからこの姿で配信しなきゃいけないってこと？
Does this mean we have to stream in this form from now on?
え、ホロライブのマスコットになるってこと？フブキも恐慌しておる。
Even Fubuki is getting scared.
え、なんか、どうしよう。どうしたらいいんだろう。
What should I do? What should I do?
え？
Eh?
なに？なに？
What? What?
フブキスコムブ歌ってってこと？
Fubuki's Scombu song?
だからライブ？
Like, live?
あ、このまま歌い続ければもししかすると歌の力で元に戻るかもしれない。
If we keep singing like this, maybe we can return with the power of song.
確かに、このお城も歌のみんなの力で立ったしね。フブキもそう思うか。
True, this castle was built by the power of everyone's songs, so Fubuki thinks so too.
ほんまか。(笑)
Really? Haha.
じゃあちょっとこのまま我々3人で歌い踊り、その力で...
Then, let's try singing and dancing with the three of us, and use that power...
この呪いを解くぞおおおお！
To break this curse!
おおおー！
Woohoo!
よし、準備だ！
Okay, preparation!
everything's gonna be alright って感じよ
everything's gonna be alright, feel it
今、噂 の bewitch you
now, bewitch you with rumors
沈む 太陽 に おはようって 言ったり
saying good morning to the setting sun
真昼 の 月 に おやすみって 言ったり
saying good night to the midday moon
いつだって僕らはちょっとズレてる
every time we're a bit off
丸い地球のせいかもね
it might be the fault of the round earth
人間事みたいじゃん…だって狐だしさ
like saying just a word, we're like foxes
そこんとこよろしくね
nice to meet you over there
世界中が輪！
the whole world is!
ってそれ無理じゃない？ってことも
that's not impossible, right?
今からホントになる
it will really happen from now on
are you ready？
are you ready?
コンコン コン
kon kon kon
yes こんな狐に化かされて
yes, fooled by such a fox
knock, knock, knock 心を開いて
knock, knock, knock, open your heart
everything's gonna be alright って感じよ
everything's gonna be alright, feel it
今、噂の bewitch you
now, bewitch you with rumors
ぎりぎりでいいじゃない？
Isn't it fine if we're just on the edge?
余裕なんてなくたって
Even without any margins to spare,
一生懸命やったら
if we give it our all,
とりあえず気持ちいいでしょ？
won't it feel good for now, at least?
どろんこでいいじゃない？
Isn't it fine if we're covered in mud?
夢を追いかけてた
We were chasing after our dreams,
あのひたむきさがあれば
as long as we had that devotion,
向かうところ敵なしなんだよ
there was no place where we had enemies.
Wow Wow Wow Wow
手を振り上げろ
Raise your hands and wave them,
忘れちゃいけないよ
you mustn't forget
本気の君のストレート
your serious, straight fastball.
Wow Wow Wow Wow
準備OK！
Ready, OK!
来いよ真ん中打ってみせるから
Pitch it right down the middle and I'll show you I can hit it.
Ah 彼方まで
Ah, all the way to the other side.
喉が渇いたらさ
If your throat gets dry,
水道でいいじゃない？
isn't tap water fine?
頭から被って子供みたいにはしゃいで
Pouring it over our heads and playing like kids,
そんな夏は過ぎた
those summers have passed.
いつか大人になった
Someday we became adults,
でもなんだかそのスーツは
yet somehow those suits
とても暑そうに見えるよ
look like they're so hot to wear.
Wow Wow Wow Wow
今度は君だ
this time, it's your turn.
その先に見据えているのは
What you're staring at ahead
あたしのストレート
is my fastball.
Wow Wow Wow Wow
思い切り投げつけてみるからさ
I'll show you I can throw with all my might.
どこいくのか？よく見てて
Where will it go? Watch closely.
今必要なのは
What we need right now
根性と汗だ
is guts and sweat.
取り返しに行こう
Let's go take it back,
あの晴れ渡った空のgame
that game under the clear blue sky.
Wow Wow Wow Wow
手を振り上げろ
raise your hands and wave them,
忘れちゃいけないよ
you mustn't forget
本気のまっすぐdon't be afraid
your serious, straight pitch, don't be afraid.
Wow Wow Wow Wow
準備OK！
Ready, OK!
来いよ真ん中打ってみせるから
Pitch it right down the middle and I'll show you I can hit it.
Ah 空高く
Ah, high up in the sky.
Wow Wow Wow Wow
はー、スコんビーズ楽しかったけど、この体大変だよお！
Phew, being Sconbu was fun, but this body is so tough!
いやでも、スコんぶなかなかやりおるやん、白上の体を使いこなしておる！
Man, Sconbu is pretty good at handling Shirakami's body!
でも、やっぱね、白上の体が恋しいよね！
But still, you miss Shirakami's body, right?
おお、やっぱりそうだよね、スコんぶはこの体じゃなきゃね！
Oh, right, Sconbu's gotta be in this body!
でも、白上もね、こんな経験なかなか無いからさ、最後にちょっと記念撮影しようや、ねえ！
And since Shirakami doesn't get experiences like this often, let's take a commemorative photo at the end, okay?
よし、じゃあちょっと持ち上げてもらおうかな
Alright, then could you lift me up?
持ち上げてくれ、よっと！
Lift me up, heave-ho!
ういしょ、わ、浮いた！お写真撮って！
Whoa, I'm floating! Take a picture!
よいしょ、ありがと、おろしてくれ、よいしょ、はあ！
Heave-ho, thanks, put me down, heave-ho, phew!
じゃあそろそろね、元の体にお互い戻りましょう！
Well, it's about time we both return to our original bodies!
よいしょ、たぶんねこの辺に来れば、魔法陣が出てくるはずだから、では行きますよ！
Alright, if we come around here, a magic circle should appear, so here we go!
いでよ、魔法陣！
Appear, magic circle!
戻れるのか！？
Can we return!?
あ！戻れたーー！やったー！よかったよかった！
Ah, we returned! Yay! Thank goodness!
スコン部、ちゃんとスコン部？わあ、すこ
Sconbu, are you properly Sconbu? Wow...
やっぱその体が一番いいね、ねえ、ありがと！
That body really is the best, hey, thank you!
よし、じゃあスコン部、この後一緒に歌いたいけども、次の曲は白上頑張るから、またね、あのステージの前で応援しててくれ！気をつけて！
Alright, Sconbu, I'd love to sing together after this, but Shirakami's gonna work hard on the next song, so cheer for me in front of the stage! Take care!
かわいい、かわいい
Cute, cute.
もう去り方がかわいいね、スコン部。見にきてくれてるスコン部のみんなもかわいいぞ！
Your way of leaving is so cute, Sconbu. All the Sconbus who came to watch are cute too!
ではではでは、まだまだ応援してくれますよね？ねえ、ありがとー！
Now then, you'll keep cheering for us, right? Hey, thanks!
よし、では次の曲いきましょう、次の曲はレター！
Alright, let's move on to the next song, the next song is Letter!
Dear my friend ありがとうを込めて
Dear my friend, putting gratitude into
君の名前がかけがえのない光
your name is my irreplaceable light.
見失ったって 頑張れるだって 言葉ひとつでも願い叶うと
Even if I lose sight, I can do my best, believing that even a single word will make wishes come true.
世界と呼ばれたって 生きる理由はなんです
Even if it's called a world, what is the reason to live?
へこんだって 見失ったって
Even if I get depressed, even if I lose my way,
また私を照らしてくれる
you shine upon me once again.
心は静かに満たされて 気絶しちゃいそうです
My heart is quietly filled, I feel like I might faint.
一生懸命な姿に 何度も勇気もらったから
Because I received courage so many times from your hard-working figure,
今度は私がお返しになりたい
this time, I want to return the favor.
舞台千熱量の散華
The passionate fervor of the stage's glorious end,
Dear my wave 大好きが溢れた この想い手紙に書いて送ります
Dear my wave, overflowing with love, I write these feelings in a letter and send them.
夢、マイデイ、夢を叶えて 君の笑顔が私の
Dreams, my day, making dreams come true, your smile is my...
夢、マイデイ、夢を叶えて 君の笑顔が私のエール
Dreams, my day, making dreams come true, your smile is my cheer!
dear my fave ,
「 ありがとう ! 」 を 込め て
With a "Thank you!" put into it,
君 の 名 は 、
Your name is,
かけがえ の ない 希望
an irreplaceable hope.
リアル だって 頑張れる !
I can do my best because it's real!
だって 、 言葉 ひとつ で 胸 が 躍る
Because a single word makes my heart leap,
“ 限界 ” と 呼ばれ たって いい
it's fine if they call it my "limit."
生きる 理由 なん です
It's the reason I live.
へこん だって 見失っ たって
Even if I get depressed or lose sight,
また 私 を 照らし て くれる
you illuminate me once again.
心臓 わしづかみ さ れ て
My heart gets grabbed so tight
気絶 し ちゃい そう です
I feel like I'm going to faint.
一生懸命 な 姿 に
From your hard-working figure,
何回 も 勇気 もらっ た から
I've received courage so many times,
今度 は 私 が エール に なり たい
so now I want to become your cheer!
捧げ 全力 量 の 讃歌
Offering a hymn of my full strength!
dear my fave ,
「 大好き ! 」 が 溢れ た
Overflowing with "I love you!"
この 想い 、 手紙 に 書い て 贈り ます
I'll write these feelings in a letter and send them.
you made my day
夢 を 叶え て 君 の 笑顔 が 、 私 の 原動力
making dreams come true—your smile is my energy!
you will always be the first star in my heart
どこ まで も つい て ゆく よ !
I'll follow you anywhere!
i 'm your biggest fan
i'm your biggest fan!
“ 幸せ ” って “ 君 と 出逢っ て 過ごす 日々 ” だ と
"Happiness" is defined as "days spent meeting you"
定義 さ れ た !
as it was defined!
会え ない 時間 だって … 良い !
Even the time we can't meet... is good!
愛 を 育てる ん です
It nurtures our love.
どうしたって叫びたくなった
No matter what, I wanted to shout it out—
イタズラ 顔 も 最高 最高 高ッ ! !
even your mischievous face is the absolute best!!
来世 も 来 来世 まで も
Even in the next life, and the life after that,
語り継ぎ たい の です
I want to pass it on through stories.
一瞬 一瞬 が ときめく
Every single moment makes my heart flutter,
両手 に 一杯 の 想い出
with memories filling both hands.
確かめ 合え ば 寂しく ない から
If we confirm them together, we won't be lonely,
繋げ 全 絆 の 結晶
connecting the crystal of all bonds!
dear my fave ,
「 がんばっ て ! 」 なんて 言え ない
I can't just say "Do your best!"
「 大丈夫 」 の 三文字 で 伝わる か な …
I wonder if three words of "It's okay" convey it...
day by day
そう 、 君 の おかげ で 少し だけ 、 自分 を 好き に なれ た から
yes, thanks to you, I've come to like myself just a little bit more,
君らしく keep smiling and enjoy yourself
Be yourself, keep smiling and enjoy yourself.
心から願う私がいる、ひとりじゃない
I'm here wishing from the bottom of my heart, you're not alone.
dear my fave ,
「 大好き ! 」 を 集め た
Gathering up "I love you!"
愛言葉 手紙 に 書い て 贈り ます
I'll write these words of love in a letter and send them.
you made my life
夢 で 終わら ない 君 だけ が 、 君 こそ が 起こす 奇跡
not ending in a dream—you alone, you are the one who creates miracles.
you will always be the first star in my heart ☆彡
信じ て 夜空 の よう に ずっと
Believing, just like the night sky, forever.
i will follow you forever
ありったけ の 愛 を 込め て “ ありがとう ”
putting in all my love: "Thank you."
君 と いう たった 一つ の 奇跡 銀河 を 越え て 掛け合う フレーズ 輝か せ て
The single miracle that is you—crossing the galaxy, making our intersecting phrases shine!
best wishes ,
best wishes,
はい 、 という こと で
Yes, and with that,
レター に し たー !
we made it into a letter!
みんな コメント も いっぱい
Everyone, thank you so much for all your comments!
ありがとー !
Thank you!
ちょっと 息 を 吸っ て
Let me catch my breath...
はーい !
Haa-i!
いや もう 本当 に やっぱ レター は 楽しい です ね !
Man, truly, letters are just so much fun!
そして この 体 が やっぱ しっくり くる ん だー !
And this body just fits me so well~!
みんな いっぱい 盛り上がっ て くれ て ありがとう ござい まー す !
Thank you everyone for getting so hyped up with me!
ゆー !
Woo!
さてさて 、 で は もう ね 、 いい お 時間 な ので
Now then, since it's getting to be a good time,
重大 告知 、 えー 、 1 個 目 発表 し たい と 思い まー す !
I'd like to announce the first major announcement!
なん と 、 なんと なんと … 新曲 が あり まー す !
What, what, what... there's a new song!
わぁー ! 新曲 だ ! うれしい ! 新曲 だー !
Yay~! A new song! I'm so happy! A new song!
なんと なんと なんと … 新曲 が あり まー す !
What, what, what... there's a new song!
あれ 、 待って ? あれ 、 もしかして … その 声 は ? あれ ?
Huh, wait? Huh? Could it be... that voice? Huh?
あー やや や 、 あー やや !
A-ya-ya-ya, a-ya-ya-ya!
え 、 みこ さん ? セカンド ブレイド よ !
Eh, Miko-san? It's Second Blade!
どっち も 、 え 、 じゃ スカーフ の 方 が … こっち か ? こっち か ?
Both? Wait, which one is the scarf—this one? This one?
スイッチ ゃ ん !
Switcher!
え 、 じゃ スカーフ に なっ ちゃっ た の ?
Eh, did you become the scarf?
スカーフ ! スカーフ !
Scarf, scarf!
ちっちゃく なっ ちゃっ て …
You got so small...
みこ さーん ! え 、 いい こと ! あれ 、 みこ さん 、 その リボン は ね 、 あの 海外 スコンブ 、 いわゆる フレンズ な ん だ けど
Miko-san! Eh, good thing! Miko-san, that ribbon is... an overseas Sukonbu,いわゆる friends...
みこさん、あれもしかして海外…ってことは英語のスコンブってこと？エイフレ？
Miko-san, could that be overseas... meaning English Sukonbu? Aifure?
え、よくももしかしてえのんのスコンブってこと？エイフレ、エイフレ！
Eh, could it be Enon's Sukonbu? Aifure, Aifure!
なっちゃったんだ、ええとスコンブなんだよ！そっか、JPのスコンブになっちゃって…
You became that, um, it's Sukonbu! I see, you became JP's Sukonbu...
あれら二人とも、あれ？どうしたの？中さっき、本当アホみたいな呪いにかけて書いたの？
Hey, you two, huh? What happened? Earlier, did you really put some stupid curse on it and write it?
アホみたいな呪いかけたら、さっきフブサンが元の姿に戻ったでしょ？そしたらこんな風になっちゃったの！
When you put a stupid curse on it, earlier Fubu-san went back to her original form, right? And then it ended up like this!
逆に？あの呪いが返ってきたんだ！元々の呪いは二つだから割ることするのお前のせいだろ！
Conversely? That curse came back! The original curse was two, so dividing it is your fault!
お前が悪いんだよ！お前が悪いんだよ！お前が悪いんだよ！
It's your fault! It's your fault! It's your fault!
待て待て待て、何やって…
Wait, wait, wait, what are you doing...
戦うな！戦うな！
Don't fight! Don't fight!
これから！王が…
From now on! The king...
王じゃないよ。
Not the king!
これから王が新曲発表するって！
The king is going to announce a new song!
あ、そうだよ！
Ah, that's right!
新曲なんですか？
A new song?
そうなんですようふふ…なんとですね、ちょっと笑っちゃったりしたんだけど、みんなコメントも可愛くて。
That's right, hehe... Well, I ended up laughing a bit, but everyone's comments were so cute.
かわいいよ！
So cute!
当たり前じゃん！
That goes without saying!
俺ら可愛い！あた、俺ら可愛い！
We're cute! Ah, we're cute!
当たり前じゃん！
That goes without saying!
当たり前じゃん！当たり前じゃん！もうさ、
That goes without saying! I mean,
それが新しいフブミコメントさんの姿だよ。嘘だよ。
that's the new Fubumi-comment-san's appearance. Just kidding!
うそだよ！どんな！かわいい！
Just kidding! What kind of... cute!
どんなだろか、呪いといてあげる。
What is it like? I'll curse you.
おんなじ顔しないで！差別できなくなるでしょ！
Don't make the same face! We won't be able to tell you apart!
差別区別ね！
Discrimination and distinction!
差別区別！じゃあじゃあじゃないんだよ！えっとほら、
Distinction! That's not what I meant! Um, look,
その、なんだ、なんだっけ、あ、そうだそうだ、ごめんごめん、えっと…
um, what was it, ah, that's right, sorry sorry, um...
えと、こ、じゃあですね、今からちょっと新曲、え、アルバムからですね、え、福祉作詞作曲編曲レボさんの楽曲をちょっと…ええ？なんてことしてんだろ。ええ？
Um, well then, from now on, a new song, from the album, um, lyricist, composer, and arranger Revo-san's song... Eh? What am I doing? Eh?
え、Reo？Revo？総力あげていいるでしょ？
Eh, Reo? Revo? You're putting all your effort into it, right?
Revoね！わかる、わかる。
Revo! I know, I know.
わかる、わかる、わかる。
I know, I know, I know.
ほら、あ、でもすっちゃん分かりそうだけどね。
Look, ah, but Su-chan seems like she'd know.
すっちゃんわかってないよ。
Su-chan doesn't know.
わかるよ！
I know!
すっちゃんわかるもんね。心臓捧げるんだよ。
Su-chan knows, right? You offer your heart.
あ、そうかね、それ曲、曲作ってる方ですね。はい。
Ah, is that so, that's the person making the songs. Yes.
じゃあ21時30分からですね、こちらの僕らの星座という楽曲MV公開予定でございますので、そちらも…
Well then, from 21:30, the music video for our song "Bokura no Seiza" is scheduled to be released, so that too...
21時30分からね、よろしくお願いします！はすー！
From 21:30, please look forward to it! Hasu!
世界に勝ったね！
We conquered the world!
みんなよろしくね！
Everyone, please!
買えよ！聞けよ！21時から配信ございます！
Buy it! Listen to it! Stream starts at 21:00!
聞いてね！はい！はい！
Listen to it! Yes! Yes!
ってことでちょっと今から、あの…聞かせて…
So, starting now, um... let us hear...
させていただいたんだけどもう、え、みこめっとももしして来てくれるの？
We got to listen to it, but wait, will Miko and Suisei come too?
みこちゃん、ん？みこちゃんたちすかんぷだよ。
Miko-chan, hmm? Miko-chan and them are scamps.
しでよ。いつでも一緒だよ。
Do it. We're always together.
そうだよ。
That's right.
っそなんだ！じゃあ、
Is that so! Then,
一緒にじゃあちょっとパフォーマンスしてくれるの？あ、まったん！
Will you perform with me a little bit? Ah, Mattan!
あーやったー！えへへへ…
Ah, yay! Ehehehe...
ちょっとね、あの僕らの星座の前にね、あの円形ステージがあるので、そこでじゃあ一緒に踊りましょう、歌って踊りましょう。わかった？
And, before our "Bokura no Seiza", there's a circular stage, so let's dance together there, let's sing and dance. Understood?
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
じゃあそれでは聞いてください。僕らの星座、どうぞ！
Well then, please listen to it. "Bokura no Seiza", go!
始まりはきっと１つの願い それを抱いて私は生まれた
The beginning is surely a single wish, embracing it, I was born.
孤独な夜空震える指で 点と点を繋げよう
In the lonely night sky, with trembling fingers, let's connect the dots.
異次元では寂しすぎるから 私たちは広がりを求めた
In another dimension it's too lonely, so we sought expansion.
線は線となり 線は立体となり そこに距離が生まれたけれど
Lines became lines, lines became 3D, and distance was born there,
３次元ではちょっと遠すぎるから 私たちは平面に求めた
But in 3D it's a bit too far, so we sought it on a flat plane.
線は線となり 線は星座となり この夜空を繋ぐよ
Lines became lines, lines became constellations, connecting this night sky.
自分らしくいられる場所を 気づけばずっと探していた
I had been searching all along for a place where I could be myself.
煌めく星よ 小鳥ひと止め この目印に
Glittering stars, little birds stop here, at this landmark.
あの日の君がいつもそこにいたから 健気に続けなんだ
Because you of that day were always there, I could keep going valiantly.
今日まで忘れないでね 私らの星座は君がいたから生まれた
Don't forget until today, our constellation was born because you were there.
異次元では楽しすぎたから 私たちは毎日を笑った
In another dimension it was too much fun, so we laughed every day.
弱音となり 不安となり 辛い肩を回して
Turning into weakness, anxiety, rolling our tired shoulders,
自分らしく笑える場所を 気づけば闇に星は満ちた
A place where we can smile as ourselves, before we knew it the darkness was filled with stars.
重ねる歌で 想いを刻め この白羽の城壁に
Engrave your thoughts with overlapping songs onto this white-feathered rampart.
だから君がいつか自身自身の輝きを見失った時には思い出してね
So when you ever lose sight of your own brilliance, remember,
私らの星座は…
Our constellation is...
ほら 君がいるから輝く
Look, it shines because you are here.
たとえ君がいつの時を生きても
Even if you live in any era,
何かを好きになる気持ち
the feeling of falling in love with something,
大切に歌い続けてね 僕らの星座
please keep singing it dearly, our constellation.
ほら 君がいるから 生まれ夜空に輝き
Look, born because you are here, shining in the night sky,
明日へとつながる
connecting to tomorrow.
未来を目指すよ
Aiming for the future,
ともに行こう
let's go together.
始まりはきっと 一つの願い
Surely, the beginning is a single wish.
それを抱いて 私たちは
Embracing that, we
生まれた孤独な夜空 震える指で
with trembling fingers in the lonely night sky where we were born,
天と地をつなげよう
let's connect heaven and earth.
たとえ君がいつの時を生きても
Even if you live in any era,
何かを好きになる気持ち
the feeling of falling in love with something,
大切に歌い続けてね 僕らの星座
please keep singing it dearly, our constellation.
ほら 君がいるから 生まれ夜空に輝き
Look, born because you are here, shining in the night sky,
明日へとつながる
connecting to tomorrow.
未来を目指すよ
Aiming for the future,
ともに行こう
let's go together.
はい ということで もうみんな分かってたと思いますけども
Yes, so, I think everyone already knew, but
白上フブキ 初のソロライブ開催決定しました！
Shirakami Fubuki's 1st solo live has been announced!
やったー！
Yay!
もうさ みんなにしつこいぐらい言われた ソロライブやるんでしょって
Everyone kept pestering me, asking "Are you doing a solo live?"
その度に否定しなきゃいけない日々 大変苦でございました！
and having to deny it every time was so agonizing!
「ありません！」みたいなの否定し続けちゃってごめんなさい！
Sorry for having to keep denying it with "There is none!" and all that!
やりまーす！やったー！
We're doing it! Yay!
はい ということで 開催日は2025年2月13日で
Right, so, the concert date is February 13, 2025,
会場は横浜のピアアリーナMMで開催します！やったー！
and it will be held at Pia Arena MM in Yokohama! Yay!
まじか... かてが...えっ、二人さ
Seriously... Kato... wait, you two,
そのままにしていいの？ 戻すよ？戻せるよ多分。
can you leave it like that? I'll put it back? You can probably put it back.
ああ...だってさっきさ歌って...歌うっていうか踊ったから戻れるけど。大丈夫。楽しかった。
Ah... because earlier you sang... well, not sang, danced, so you can go back. It's fine. It was fun.
スコーンだもんね。
It's Scorn, after all.
なんか二人さ、歌ってたらさ、なんかさ、前でさ、ガッチャンコしそうになったの、戻って...
Like, when the two of you were singing, it looked like you were about to crash into each other at the front, so you went back...
必死にさ、笑わないように...笑ってない間邪魔にならないようにって...
Desperately trying not to laugh... trying not to get in the way while not laughing...
ごめんね？ 無言でさ、お互いアイコンタクト取りながらさ...
Sorry? Remaining silent while making eye contact with each other...
もうだめだ、笑いがこみ上げてきちゃって... もうね、スクスク笑ってて...
I couldn't take it, laughter welled up... You know, chuckling away...
必死にさ、笑わないようにこらえてたんだよ。
We were desperately trying not to laugh.
だってこんなにファンシースいちゃん初めて見たよ。
I mean, I've never seen such a fancy Suichan before.
かわいい！かわいい！もうスコーンのよろこんでます！
Cute! Cute! The Scorns are already rejoicing!
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
わあ！
Waa!
おめでとう！ありがとうございます！はい！
Congratulations! Thank you so much! Yes!
ちょっとね、先ほど、歌わせていただきました、
As I sang just moments ago...
新曲「僕らのセザ」はですね、このライブに向けて制作しました。
our new song "Bokura no Seza" was produced for this live.
フブキングダムの国家でございます！
It is the national anthem of FBKINGDOM!
そのライブでは、たぶん、きっとメビウスももちろん歌います！
At that live, I'm sure—sure, Mebius will definitely be sung too!
なので、みんなにはこの曲覚えてほしい。
So, I want everyone to memorize this song.
もしよかったら、もう1番から、もう頭からお尻までまるっとみんなで大合唱したいんですよ、しゃ長は。
If possible, Shacho wants everyone to sing along from the very first verse all the way to the end!
なので、ちょっとこの曲是非覚えて、会場のみんなで歌いましょう！
So please learn this song and let's all sing it together at the venue!
全力でおねがいします！覚えてください！
I'm begging you! Please learn it!
この後21時30分、そして24時からも掛け声配信がございますので、アルバムの中に入ってる曲なんですけど、先に覚えていただけると嬉しいです！
There will also be a call-and-response stream starting at 9:30 PM and 24:00 later today, so I'd be happy if you could learn it beforehand!
それでは続いてはですね、ライブのキービジュアルを公開します！こちら！
Now, next up, I'll reveal the key visual for the live! Here it is!
はい、もうね、めちゃめちゃかっこ可愛いい、白神を描いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Yes! They drew such a super cool and cute Shirakami for us! Thank you so much!
かっこいいよ、王様！そう、王様！王様で！
So cool, Your Majesty! Yes, Your Majesty! As the king!
マスコットのみんなの、あれ？みこめっとですか、あれは？あれスコン部だよ！
And everyone's mascot... wait, is that Micomet? No, that's Sukonbu!
そうだよ！スコン部のみんなです！公演出発は、ハッシュタグ「#DearFBKINGDOM」でどんどんポストして盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです！お願いします！
That's right! It's everyone in Sukonbu! We'd be happy if you post and hype it up using the hashtag #DearFBKINGDOM! Please do!
さらにトリミング前のイラストも公開しちゃいます！こちら！
Furthermore, we're also revealing the uncropped illustration! Here it is!
そう、足長い！じつはですね、もうすごい足長アングルで描いていただきました！もう素晴らしいです！もふもふの鐘だね？そう！鐘も鳴って、こうね、神吹雪も舞ってます！ありがとうございます！
That's right, long legs! Actually, it was drawn with an amazing long-leg angle! It's wonderful! Fluffy bells? Yes! The bells are ringing, and divine blizzards are dancing too! Thank you so much!
え、続いてはですね、チケット情報に行きましょうか！こちらをご覧ください！
Now, next up, let's go to ticket information! Please take a look at this!
はい、え、チケットはS席、A席、B席の3種類です！
Yes, tickets come in three types: S seat, A seat, and B seat!
さらに、海外スコン部向けにもZAIKOで現地チケットを販売いたします！やったー！
Furthermore, we will also sell venue tickets on ZAIKO for overseas Sukonbu! Yay!
ハイフレンズ！ウィー・ウィル・セール・ザ・べニュー・チケット・フォー・ユー！イエーイ！買ってくれたかな？海外にきみもぜひ来てくださーい！
Hi friends! We will sell the venue tickets for you! Yay! Did you buy them? Overseas friends, please come too!
現地チケットの一時先行がなんとこの後21時から開始となります！ぜひチェックしてください！チケットは先着ではなく抽選方式なので焦らずにお申し込みをお願いします！
The first pre-order for venue tickets starts tonight at 21:00! Please check it out! Tickets are determined by lottery, not first-come-first-served, so please apply without rushing!
次に配信チケット！ミコさんでは吊り席ですけど、我々スコン部はですね、ダンボールという名の家がありますのでダンボール席でございます！はい、配信チケット（ダンボール席）はSPWNとZAIKOで発表いたします！
Next, streaming tickets! Mikos have hanging seats, but we in Sukonbu have houses called cardboard boxes, so it's cardboard seats! Yes, streaming tickets (cardboard seats) will be announced on SPWN and ZAIKO!
こちらもこの後21時から販売開始なので現地に来れないよという方はですね、配信のダンボールの中から白上を応援してくれると嬉しいです！お願いします！
Sales also start tonight at 21:00, so if you can't make it to the venue, I'd be happy if you could cheer for Shirakami from inside your cardboard streaming boxes! Please!
続いて各座席のエリアマップをご覧ください！どうぞ！
Next, please take a look at the area map for each seat! Here you go!
ぴあアリーナってすごい広いんだよね！すごい！ぴあアリーナMMだよ、ちょっと未だに実感湧かないんですけども、1階がアリーナS席、2階と3階中央がA席、3階の一部と4階がB席ということで4階まである！S席、S席当てたい。S席あてです、1回。S席じゃ...のみこさんも？みこさんも？え、関係者席、用意するが？え？S席だよ、ダメです。来ちゃダメです。二人もダンボール席かもしれない！
PIA Arena is so huge, you know? Huge! Pia Arena MM, I still don't really have a sense for it, but the 1st floor is Arena S seats, the 2nd and 3rd floors center are A seats, and part of the 3rd floor and 4th floor are B seats. So it goes up to the 4th floor! S seat, S seat I want. S seat... and Mikos too? Mikos too? Eh, connection seats, can you prepare them? Eh? S seat, no. That's no good, coming is no good. Both of you might be cardboard seats too!
はい！じゃあね、チケットも出ましたので続いてはみなさんお待ちかねのグッズ情報です！こちら！
Yes! Ticket info is out, so next up is everyone's long-awaited goods info! Here!
まずは、白上フブキ1stソロライブ「FBKINGDOM応援セット」をご紹介！
First, I'll introduce the Shirakami Fubuki 1st Solo Live FBKINGDOM Support Set!
こちらですね、あの、応援セットの入国証明キーホルダー以外、あ、あとTシャツ以外は、実はペンライトとスコン部タオル全部白上がデザインさせていただきました！おー、すごい！
Other than the arrival light-up keychain and T-shirt, the penlight and Sukonbu towel were all designed by Shirakami herself! Wow, amazing!
え、まずはですね、こちらのセットなんですけども、え、このセットを買うと、入国証明キーホルダーがついてきます。
First, regarding this set, if you buy this set, it comes with the arrival light-up keychain.
国民ペンライトはですね、運営さんと一緒にこんな感じにお願いします！この形でお願いします！って白上がね、もう土下座して頼んだ結果作っていただいたペ、ペンライトでございます。
The national penlight was designed like this in collaboration with management, please! This is the penlight Shirakami dogeza'd and asked them to make for the live!
今回のライブテーマのフブキングダムにふさわしい王冠をあしらったデザインとなってまして、ライブ会場で国民の皆さんがね、フルライトにぴったりな仕上がりとなっております！
It has a crown design fit for the live theme FBKINGDOM, so it will look just right with everyone at the live venue having full lights!
そう、形はね、スコン部なんだけど、中間に国のね、マークが入って...
That's right, the shape is Sukonbu, but inside it has a national crest mark!
ぜひぜひ振ってくださら～い！
Please check it out!
そしてTシャツはですね 今回の公演特別仕様です。
And the T-shirt is specially designed for this concert.
特にね背面にはですね白髪みの尻尾、尻尾と言いますか、星マークと、えー描き下ろしのイラストが実はいってるんです。
On the back, it actually features a tail, or rather, a star mark and illustrations!
本当だ！はい、ここにTシャツの隅っこに落書きしていいですか？って言ったら、いいよって言ってくれたので白髪みがちょっと書かせていただきましたー！
And so Shirakami got permission to draw it in the corner of the T-shirt!
嬉しい。
Yay!
はい、ぜひねライブといえばTシャツということで
Yes, when it comes to live concerts, T-shirts are a must.
皆さんにお召し来てきてほしいなと思っております。
We hope you'll all come wearing them!
そして、スコンブタオルはフードをかぶるとみんなスコンブー！
And as for the Sukonbu towel, once you put the food on, you become a true Sukonbu!
カワチイスコンブになれちゃいまっすー。
You become a cute Sukonbu.
ただねスカーフが確か無いので、海外のね、あのスコンブは「あれリボンじゃないの？」なんですけどもね
Since there's no hood, overseas Sukonbu might wonder, "Is that not a ribbon?"
まああのよければこちらも着てきてくれると嬉しいです。
Well, if you'd like, we'd be happy if you wore this too!
これねあのスカーフのところがボタンで止めれるようになってますので、Tシャツの上からでも羽織ってこれまーす。
The scarf part can be fastened with a button, so you can wear it over your T-shirt.
よろしくお願いしますー。
We'd appreciate your support!
はい、で応援セットを買ってくれた方には入国証明キーホルダーが特典でついてきまーす。これねあのパスポートに押すね入国スタンプをイメージした
And for those who purchase the support set, you'll receive a special immigration certificate keychain!
感じとなっておりまーす。ね、これを付ければあなたも国民の仲間入り？ニュククしてくれ！
If you attach this, you can officially join the citizenship!
はい。
Yes!
そしてグッズはまだまだございます。こちら！ってーん！
And there are still more goods! Here they are!
えー応援セットはですね単品でも販売させていただきます。
The support set items will also be available for individual purchase.
別売りのカンバッチとですねフブキングダム腕章がなんとこちらにはございますー。
The separately sold can badges feature gorgeous, glittering Fubukingdom designs!
えーカンバッチは金木犀をあしらった豪華なカンバッチとなっておりまーす。もうね最近スコンブの皆さんがね痛バック
Lately, many Sukonbu have been making Ita-bags,
作ってくれたりとか夏にね白髪みがあの推し活グッズとしてちょっとあのミコメットとねあの、おそろっちのあのカバンをださせていただきましたのでね
and in the summer, we released Oshi-katsu goods like the miconetto and matching bags,
ちょっとそちらにはぜひあの、このカンバッチで、えー痛バック作っていただきたいなと思っておりまーす。
so we hope you'll use these can badges to make Ita-bags!
そしてフブキングダム腕章はですね応援セットと合わせてちょっと国民の清掃に必要なアイテムかなと思いましたー！ぜひねあの腕に、ねつけてきてほしいなと思っております。
And the Fubukingdom armbands are essential items for citizens' uniforms, so we hope you'll wear them on your arm!
なんかちょっと清掃感、清掃してきている感が
It gives a formal, uniform-like feel.
スーツで来るの？
Suits? Wearing suits?
ちょっと動きにくいかもだけどでもスーツもかっこいいかもしれない。
That might be hard to move in, but suits are cool too.
なんかそういうのってなんかおしゃれな感じで来てきてくれると嬉しいです。
Dressed in such stylish outfits, we'd be thrilled if you came to see us!
えーそしてですねこちらカンバッチとフブキングダム腕章は単品、単体のみの販売となっておりますのでね先ほど紹介した応援セットには含まれませんのでそちらご注意ください。お願いしますー。
And please note that the can badges and armbands are sold individually, so they are not included in the support set.
さらにさらにございます12月！こちらです。じゃーん！
And even better, starting in December, we have these! Ta-da!
えーこちらですねアクリルジオラマスタンドは白髪みとスコンブたちでフブキングダムの世界観を再現することができます。
The acrylic diorama stand lets you recreate the Fubukingdom worldview with Shirakami and the Sukonbu.
なんとこちら好きな位置に差し替えも可能なので、ちょっとマスコットこの位置がいいなとか自分だけのアクリルジオラマ作ってみてください。
You can place the mascot wherever you like, so try making your own custom diorama!
そしてタペストリーなんですけど、実これよーく見るとアクリルジオラマスタンドと違う点があるんですよ。
And as for the tapestry, if you look closely, it's actually different from the diorama stand!
さあどこでしょう？どこ？
What could it be?
特別でしょう。ち、ち、ち、ち、ち、ち、スカーフの色！
The color of the scarf!
ブーブー違います。
Boo-boo, incorrect!
え、手袋狐サインになっている。
It's the fox sign on the chest!
おお！すごいみこさん！正解！
Oh! Amazing, Mikosan! Correct!
なんとですねタペストリーの白髪みは、左手が狐サインになってますー。
And the Shirakami on the tapestry has a fox sign with her left hand!
こちらねアクリルジオラマスタンドとタペストリーで2種類のキービジュアルを楽しめますので、ぜひどちらもおうちに置いてください。
Since you can enjoy two different key visuals with the diorama and tapestry, we hope you'll display both at home!
よろしくお願いしますー。
Thank you so much!
そしてタロハンカチはですねフブキングダムの紋章、ま国章ですね使用しておりましてクールなデザインとなっております。ライブ以外の普段使いもできるデザインかなと思っておりますので色んな場所でね使ってほしいでーす。
And finally, some important notices! Please pay attention!
はい。
Yes!
そしてそしてですね最後に注意事項でーす。気をつけるんですよ。販売期間はこの後21時から11月25日の18時までとなっておりまーす。
The sales period is from today until November 25th at 6:00 PM!
そしてさらに注意していただきたいのがグッズの発送時期についてです。先行発送グッズはライブの前に届く予定ですが受注販売のグッズはライブのあとにお届けでございます。
Also, please note that advance-order goods will arrive before the live, while made-to-order goods will arrive after the live.
また先行発送グッズと受注販売のグッズを一緒のカートに入れて購入することができません。なのであの別会計でお願いしますー。あの先行、先に買ったあとに受注販売のグッズを購入していただけると嬉しいです。別会計忘れずに！
Also, you cannot purchase advance and made-to-order goods in the same cart, so please make separate checkouts!
詳しくは公式X販売サイト、公式特設サイトをご確認ください！
Be sure to check the official X, sales site, and special goods site for details!
あのさ、ミコメットさ
Those Mikocommet...
もっくんとすきあらばすぐそうやって争うんだから、ミコメットは。
Mokkun and Mikomet always quarrel right away.
相変わらず。
They're always like that.
え？どっちも？どっちも悪いだろ全く。
Huh? Both are bad.
すぐセットでいちゃいちゃすんだから。
Always making a fuss over nothing.
あ、違うかビジネスかこれもう。
Oh, wait, is this business too?
そしてそして、え、白上フブキファーストアルバム
And now, we have some additional information regarding...
『FBKINGDOM Blessing』のプリンセスに続いて、
"FBKINGDOM Blessing"!
追加情報がございます。だざー！
Ta-da!
本日、通常版の店舗特典の絵柄を初公開！いぇーい！やったー！
Today, we're revealing the store-specific bonus goods for the regular edition! Yay!
店舗別の特典ですね、素敵な特典が盛りだくさんなのでぜひチェックしてくださいね。
There are lots of different retailer-specific bonuses, so be sure to check them out!
さらに、ででん！大好評いただきすでに予約は終了してるんですけども、数量限定版の外箱のデザインがこちら、こっち！こっち！こっちです！うー！
And what's more, pre-orders for the quantity-limited outer box design—which has already received so much love—is right here! Woo!
うー！
Woo!
あ、いや、こちらもね、すごいかっこいい感じに、おしゃれな感じにしていただきました！
This one also turned out super stylish and cool!
そしてさらにこちら！でゅー！表情寒いイラストを使用したアルバムのジャケットのデザインが到着しましたー！えがおー！かわいい！
And finally, here is the jacket design for the album featuring this cool and slightly cold illustration! Yay, cute!
皆さん、こちらアルバムご購入本当にありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for purchasing the album!
通常版もございます、よろしくお願いします！が、こちらは届くのお楽しみにしてください！
The regular edition will be available too, so please look forward to its release!
やったね！
Yay!
ふふ、ありがとうございます。
Thank you, Fox-san!
そして最後に、本日よりこちら、ごご、国王への忠誠を叫ぼう！ハッシュタグキャンペーンを実施します！
And lastly, starting today, we're launching a hashtag campaign to shout out your loyalty to the King!
ハッシュタグ、「#FBキングダムに納税」をつけて、“フブキングダム”を布教しよう！フブキングダム王国（白上フブキ）ってどんな人？あなたが考える王国のフブキングダムの設定とはなど、テキストコメント、ファンアート、動画投稿などなんでも大歓迎です！
Use the hashtag "#FBKINGDOMダムに納税" to spread the word about FBKINGDOM and show your support across social media!
優れた納税者には国王からお言葉の言をいただけるかも…？対象プラットフォーム：X、TikTok、YouTubeショート、これ納税とありますけども、ま、お、いつものね、応援コメントですとか、ファンアート、動画投稿などなんでも、こちらハッシュタグフブキングダムに納税をつけて投稿をお願いします！
"Tax payments" can be anything—like your usual cheering comments, fan art, video posts, whatever you like! Just add the hashtag and share!
納税！
Tax payments?
ので、配信とかでちょっと、あの白上が「あ、これいいかも」って思ったやつにはちょっと紹介させていただくかもしれないので！えー！ということは納税の配信しなきゃ！
If Shirakami happens to find a post during her stream and thinks, "Oh, this is good!", she might even feature it, so please make sure to post!
ありがとうございます！ぜひ一言投稿してください！
Thank you so much! Please don't forget to post!
はい、ということで、さあ、すべての告知が終わっちゃいまして、ついにソロライブ告知しちゃった。
Alright, so all the announcements are done, and we've finally announced the solo live!
おめでとう！
Congrats!
あまり走りに来ぬの、来ぬのを。なんだ、なんだ。ありがとう、ありがとう。なんか、すいちゃんの背中を見て、みこちゃんの背中を見て、
Don't run too fast ahead of me! Thank you, thank you! Seeing Suichan's back, and Miko-chan's back...
いや、すいちゃんはまだこれからだね。すいちゃんがね。
Well, Suichan's journey comes first...
これからだね、みこちゃんの背中を見送った後に、またすいちゃんがいて、でそれを追いかける形で、で
And then Miko-chan's back will be seen off, and then Suichan's will be there, and I'll chase after that...
ちょっとね、なんかフミコメットさんでこうやってなんか、いろいろライブの発表ができたら嬉しかったなと思います。
And if I could announce various live shows through Fumikomet-san like this, I'd be so happy, you know.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
はい、そしてもう21時なので、多分そろそろ、あの販売とかね、開始してる方かと思います。よろしくお願いします！こちらは届くのお楽しみにしてください！
And it's already 9 PM, so I'm sure some of you are already starting sales, right? Thank you so much!
ということで、じゃ、本日は以上です。
So that's all for today!
はい、2人とも最後に本当に元に戻らなくて大丈夫？あん？
Wait, are you two really not going back to your normal selves? Are you okay?
じゃあ最後はじゃあ、ね、これでバイバイして終わろうと思います。
Well then, let's say goodbye with this!
いきますよ、せーの！バイバーイ！バイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイバイ！
Here we go, ready, set— Bye-bye!